Thank You, Jesus, for my joy.
This is joy - joy everlasting.
This shows today is the day of joy for your life.
Today is the day of joy for my life.
Today my enemy has made a big mistake.
Today is the day of my salvation,
the day of my breakthrough because Jesus is alive.
Thank You, Jesus!
Give thanks to Him.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Welcome to the arena of liberty.
Welcome to the presence of the living Jesus.
No matter what you have been facing up to now,
no matter the trouble you have been having so far,
today you will know that Jesus is aware.
Say, "Neighbour, Jesus is aware of my situation".
Whatever has been happening to me so far, He is in control.
It is for my advancement.
It is for my breakthrough.
Give thanks to Jesus for that.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Hallelujah.
Have your seat in His presence.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We are serving a faithful and true God.
Whatever people must have said about you,
whatever your situation must have told you,
today you will know the truth about yourself.
I am here, ready for the battle.
I am ready for the battle.
I am ready for victory.
Brethren, the reason why so many people in the Church today are weak
is because they are not armed for battle.
The first step to be strong is to realise that life is a battleground.
That is why you have been experiencing all these things because life is a battleground.
There is no neutral ground.
Say, "Neighbour, there is no neutral ground".
There is no hideout.
The purpose of God in your life cannot be fulfilled without the heat of trials.
It can be sickness, affliction, joblessness - just name it.
The purpose of God in your life can never be fulfilled without a battle.
Prepare yourself for battle.
Say, "Neighbour, prepare yourself for battle -
for your business, home and destiny.
Prepare yourself for battle".
Life is not perfect.
We are living in a world where the enemy will never allow
God's purpose in our lives to be fulfilled without putting up a battle.
You need to put up a battle.
That is why you are here and the battle is the Lord's.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Be ready for the battle.
Be ready for victory.
This brings us to the title of our message today: THE BELIEVER'S CONFLICT.
Tell your neighbour, "The Believer's Conflict".
Let me take you to the Book of Joshua 24; I start my reading from verse 14.
"Now therefore, fear the Lord, serve Him in sincerity and in truth,
and put away the gods which your fathers served on the other side of the River and in Egypt.
Serve the Lord."
Verse 15.
"And if it seems evil to you to serve the Lord,
choose for yourselves this day whom you will serve,
whether the gods which your fathers served that were on the other side of the River,
or the gods of the Amorites, in whose land you dwell.
But as for me and my house, we will serve the Lord."
Verse 18.
"And the Lord drove out from before us all the people,
including the Amorites who dwelt in the land.
We also will serve the Lord, for He is our God."
Last verse.
"But Joshua said to the people, 'You cannot serve the Lord, for He is a holy God.
He is a jealous God; He will not forgive your transgressions nor your sins'."
Let someone say, "The Believer's Conflict".
The man of God Prophet T.B. Joshua says that we cannot separate warfare from salvation
because true salvation puts us into direct conflict with satan.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The moment we make a true conversion to Jesus,
satan hates us the same way he hates Jesus.
When we are truly saved, we are engaged in a phenomenal battle.
The moment you took a heart decision to commit your life to Jesus,
total commitment to Jesus, you have declared war against the devil.
By identifying yourself to Jesus Christ of Nazareth, you have made satan your bitter enemy.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
This world is not my home; I am just passing through.
Once Jesus Christ purchases us, Prophet T.B. Joshua says that we become aliens, strangers
and there is a barrier between us and everything here on earth.
Once Jesus purchases us with His blood, we become aliens, strangers, foreigners
What do I mean?
You will not go where Jesus is not welcome.
You will not say what Jesus would not want you to say.
You will not do what Jesus would not want you to do.
You will only go where Jesus wants you to go.
The battle is the Lord’s.
Take your position.
Victory is certain.
We are spirit beings living in a physical body,
learning to live in a natural world dominated by satan.
He rules by sin, he fights in sin and sin is his weapon.
But glory be to God, in the name of Jesus, we have the victory!
But glory be to God, in the name of Jesus, I have the victory!
The best antidote to the poison of satan is to walk in the Spirit.
Walk in the Spirit.
Pray in the Spirit.
Move in the Spirit.
To walk in the Spirit, the key is not to suppress the flesh but to surrender to the Holy Spirit.
The instruction for such walk is entirely guided and regulated by the Spirit of Jesus.
How?
The Bible says we listen to the testimony of our conscience
because our heart is controlled by the Holy Spirit
In each step, each direction, each choice you make,
intimation and suggestion comes from the Holy Spirit -
the Commander, the Controller, the Instructor for such action be performed.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Say to your neighbour, "Prepare your heart.
Keep your heart".
That victory is there already for those who recognise it.
Let a smile light up your face.
That victory is already there.
That victory is already here for those who recognise it.
Our heart is a communication point, contact point, landing point for the Holy Spirit.
But today, because of many fleshly desires,
many hearts today have become a conflict room between flesh and spirit,
conflict between hate and love,
conflict between faith and doubt.
That is why the Bible says that our values need to be tested against facts and experiences.
A man may profess, “I’m a Christian”, but not such in heart.
A man may come out and say, “I’m a born again”, but not such in heart.
We know we are totally committed to Jesus Christ when that commitment is tested.
Jesus needs to test our commitment and the genuineness of our faith.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When we turn our Bible to the Book of Matthew 19:16-22,
we have a case of a rich, young ruler
who came to Jesus to express his zeal, his commitment to the Kingdom of God
and said to Jesus, “Lord, what can I do to inherit eternal life?”
Jesus answered by sending a declaration, a probing declaration to check the state of his heart
and said to the man, “Well done. But if you want to be perfect, there is something you need to do.
Go, take your possessions, sell them, give them to the poor, come and follow Me -
rewards for you in Heaven”.
There was a conflict in the heart of the man.
But the Bible says, he went back sorrowful because he had great possessions.
What can we say about that?
If our actions are motivated by self-interest, we are mortgaging tomorrow’s joy.
Doing something as a matter of commitment to God does not involve any condition attached.
If you make God one of those things, then your commitment to God will be partial, not total.
When your loyalty towards God enters into conflict with money, position, relationship, comfort,
you are likely to sit on the fence and become indifferent,
especifically when holding onto your faith is painful.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Such was the case of the people of Israel when they entered the promised land.
They said to Joshua, “We shall serve the Lord, our God”
and Joshua said to them, “You shall not be able to serve the Lord”.
Why did he say that? It wasn’t harsh.
The Bible says, he saw that there was a conflict in their heart between flesh and spirit.
There was a conflict as to know whether to give to God a total commitment or not.
As a leader in righteousness who conquered all the enemies,
Joshua knew that our responsibility to God is a commitment and fellowship rather than sacrifice.
Therefore, he urged them to give a total commitment to God - the only Source of salvation.
Say, "Neighbour, no matter what comes, no matter what happens, total commitment to Jesus -
the only Source of salvation - my Deliverer, my Protector - He is faithful.
Faith in Him is not a risk but a sure and practical act.
I want you to turn to your neighbour and say, "Neighbour, will you be ready to serve the Lord?
Are you ready?"
Today, many show great zeal out of mere conviction but lack fundamental roots in God.
Faith is our root in God.
It takes the grace of God Almighty to maintain your confession of faith
for when the heat, the vicissitudes, trials of this world come with their choking hands,
that unstable zeal is choked.
Glory be to God Almighty, as a believer, victory is yours today.
Victory is mine today.
The Holy Spirit uses my heart to guide my soul before I become what I confess.
I want you to stand up for a while.
You have to make a declaration. Are you ready for that?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You are not alone.
You are here today. Jesus knows the reason you are here today.
Jesus knows your past – nothing hidden.
He knows your present, the state of your mind.
He knows your future - nothing is hidden from Him.
A resolve to do whatever proper thing it takes separates the weak from the strong.
Joshua was a conqueror because his heart was for God.
He was determined.
Are you ready for the heart decision?
Are you ready to fight for your destiny?
Are you ready to fight for your career?
Are you ready to stand against that devil tormenting your life?
You have to know that he is a defeated foe; he knows it and you know it.
Say, “I will follow Jesus”.
Say, “I will serve Jesus”.
Say, “I will love Jesus”.
Say, “I and my family, we shall serve the Lord.
This is my declaration; this is my commitment – total, not partial.
Total – I will serve the Lord.
I stand on this commitment, no matter what happens, no matter what comes.
Thank You, Jesus!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You may be seated.
Faith is not a hobby.
There is no alternative to faith – no substitute, no shortcut to faith.
Faith is the means of victory.
You cannot grow in faith if you don’t make a total commitment to Jesus.
Total commitment is what Jesus requires through the Gospel because we serve God with our heart.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Partial commitment cannot defeat satan in battle.
That is why the Scripture says to you and I, “Watch and pray without ceasing”.
How do we watch and pray?
To watch and pray is to discipline your heart before you pray.
How do we discipline our heart?
The man of God, Prophet T.B. Joshua, says to you and I
that when the Word of God dominates your mouth, it will dominate your heart.
When the Word dominates your heart, it will influence your behaviour, your conduct.
You will fear no more.
Controlling your mediation when you read the Bible,
that enables you to control your attitude, your utterances.
Say, “God’s Word refreshes my mind. God’s Spirit renews my strength”.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Now, this is the final battle.
Tell your neighbour, "This is the final battle".
Today, I have taken the decision to fear no more, to worry no more.
I know that all that has been happening to me was for a purpose.
Today, I am in the land of liberty.
Today, I believe Jesus Christ is alive.
I am here to declare the faithfulness of Christ in my life.
Victory, salvation is mine.
When you give a total commitment to Jesus,
Jesus will take up all the devil’s challenges against your life.
Today, I say to you: Congratulations!
Say, "Neighbour, congratulations!"
Shake your hands and say, "Congratulations! Thank you for not giving up!
Hold on to your faith.
Keep to your faith because any moment from now, you will see Jesus Christ at work in our midst".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Tell your neighbour, "Christianity is not a religion;
it is a relationship with the God of mercy, the God of compassion, the God of love".
So whoever you are here today, look to Him.
Engage your heart and give thanks to Him for His victory
because what you are about to receive is by pure grace.
He has won the battle for you and me.
He has made you worthy.
The devil has been lying to you so many times but today you know,
"I will declare God’s faithfulness".
May God bless His Word, in Jesus’ name.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
TT: Mel Flowers 09/01/2019
RV: Pavel Tatyana Zheleznyakov 26/01/2019